Welcome back.
And the previous lesson, we saw how to send data.
Using the what you virtual comport in this lesson, we're going to create a new project and then send
data and receive data as well.
We're going to see our X and T X using the compote to keep the mic setup is exactly the same.
But because I want a new project rather than, you know, change that I want so that I can upload or
attach to a different project.
We start from scratch again.
So come over here.
New project.
And then I'll open this, I'll say no.
Over here.
Oh, come over here.
Penult, clapping out.
Oh, say yes.
And then I'll start off with my USP initialization.
I'll come to USP, oh, TGF this device only.
And then I'll come to middleware USP device.
What we're looking for is the virtual comport.
We leave everything the same.
And then we go to our system, core RACC, high speed extend or we use the crystal or the ceramic resonator.
Right.
Everything else should be left the same.
And then I'll come to clock.
Um, let's in fact, let's enable our one of our LCD.
I'll quote from Rome, fifteen.
I don't know which colitis, but I just said it to GPL you output so that we can turn on reality and
I'll rename this
to LCD so that we can identify it as well.
Okay.
And then I'm going to go to a configuration and we have this here asking whether we want to resolve
the issues or two particularly I'll click.
Yes.
Or go out here and it's going to do it on its own.
And then I'm going to bump this up to to six.
You can you can leave yours.
All that matters is you've selected high speed extend all over here.
And I know why you're using the PLL clock.
Okay, so then we go to project manager.
I'm going to increase the heap and the and the stack.
Oh.
At once you.
And then add once you both.
Yeah.
And then I'm going to create a project name.
I'll call this USP school.
Virtual comport r, x, t, x.
And then I select my two chain SDM 30 to Kubi D, E, and then I'll click over here to generate.
It's generating on the routes may corrupt to previous generated previous generated projects.
I wonder why I'm getting this warning.
Hard to say.
Yes.
Click over here to open the project.
Launch.
This is my this is my projects, I've cleaned up the comment I'm going to build just to make sure everything
works because of the warning I saw earlier.
OK, it's all good, right?
So, um, let's go back to our CDC.
I have to see fall and see the functions we have available to us.
Okay, let's see.
We're looking for the receiver function.
There is the USC X buffer efforts.
This is, uh, this is a buffer.
Okay.
Looking for functions.
CDC, in its efforts, the in it control efforts and, um, receive efforts.
OK.
So this function is statically defined, meaning it is.
It is constrained to just this fall.
But we want to be able to access this function in fouse outside of this external fault, such as?
Oh, it may not see far.
So one way we can get around this is to create a callback function for this.
So I'm going to go to the interface for all of this CDC underscore I that see and then define a callback.
So to find the CDC, I f the C, I think I should be able to.
Right.
Click and go to the, uh.
We need to go to the dot h file of this.
Yeah, let's see.
I'll come over here.
That will click.
Okay.
This did not age four, okay?
So we're going to define a new fall here callback function, and when we include this dot h fall to
any other file, we'll be able to use that for the function.
So we're going to, um, use the word key word so that this will always exist and then we can re implement
it in our main dot.
See.
So same week, CDC underscore.
Receive Kobuk.
And then there's.
Which will make it take two arguments.
The buffer pointed to the buffer.
To be specific.
And then the length you end.
Two.
On a score t like this.
So does dot age fall.
So this has to exist in the dots.
Yes.
Well, we can just keep it empty and then put its proper implementation in domain.
So, um, this is how a new function of copy, the header.
The function header.
We are coming to re implement over here.
We can keep it up here if we want or just paste this over here.
So we have a new function.
This function is called receive callback, which included this to our CDC.
I f c for.
So what we want to do is call this callback function of ours one of our data's received.
So I'm going to copy this function name and then come to a water, receive our CDC receive function
here.
This is the CDC received.
And when it received the packet, I'll come down here and then call our function.
Remember, our function takes two arguments.
The buffer so is the same as the same buffer that is here.
And then the length, the length here, we can just pass length the address of the length.
Oh, we can just see.
Yeah.
2.0.
We can pass the address.
It's fine like this.
So because all function is, um, it is define us weak.
We've got to do the proper implementation in me.
I'm going to copy this and then go to Maine.
And this means that you can have your own implementation, remember?
And then, um, I'll put it somewhere in Maine.
Oh, put it down here.
Oh, don't hit hideous.
I can put it up here.
And then delete the weak key word over here.
So for our experiment, we can simply echo the data back to the transmitter.
To do this, we can use the transmit F.
S function we saw earlier.
Also the CDC over here.
Transmit.
Underscore efforts.
And then we can pass the buffer over here.
S first document.
And then the length over here.
The second argument.
So this means whenever we send data, we should see it echoed back to the transmitter.
And I hope you understand this.
This is just callback function in callback function is simply do something right, do something.
So if you don't want to see, um, the data I could back, you can disable this and just see reality
such that whenever you receive data, just the LCD will be will be lit.
So we can see Harl underscore GPI you.
And then remember we um, we set one of our early days.
We can toggle it.
So we say torgau pain and then we can see GPL.
You underscore ality, underscore port and then GPL, you the dependence GPL you Ellie Dippin GPL you
on underscore early dippin a thing that is PD fifteen with it.
So if you have more things you want to do whenever data is received, you can add it here.
But we can have the echo as well.
Right.
And that's going to be our main function is just empty.
We're doing it in the Kobuk that we've created.
So let's build and see what we have.
Collected by here to build.
We have a number of errors.
Okay, so this one here, how GPL you were Togo in GPL, you report.
I think you play a live report is not spelled properly.
Capital letters.
Some of them need to be smaller letters.
OK.
Ellie, DGP, your posts should be DGP, your port.
Over here.
And then early, Depayin simply added Dippin.
Okay, let's pivot again.
Click over here.
And then the reason we have the warning is we've got include the USP, CDC.
I f dot h.
Come over here and see.
Include USP device, speedy underscore, CDC underscore I f dot h.
Like this.
So let's build a click over here to build.
It's Putin.
Now, we've got no arrow, no warning.
Click here to get it onto our board.
So like this.
We'll see.
Okay.
Over here.
And it says waiting for the probe of connection.
OK.
Download verified successfully, so it's flush the port.
I'm going to disconnect the debugger.
And then we can test it out.
So let's go ahead and and test out our federal comb, our X, T, X over here, we want to test out
receiving and transmitting of the data.
Um, before we do that, um, let's check what a callback implementation looks good.
OK?
We said this is a callback.
You can do something, but we basically want to echo back what we receive and then turn on the ality.
This Elegy pianist connected to the blue LTT of the Discovery boat over here in a mock in a wall made
wall one.
I'm going to put a bit of delay here.
We'll see how all on a score delay.
And then I'm going to pass this.
A five hundred here.
Okay.
And then let's go to our CDC dot.
I file this one here.
We made a lot of changes here.
This the main change that we did.
Let's see.
Does OK over here to point to because it's a point to the CDC underscore receive efforts.
I'm going to change this and to learn index.
You like this.
OK, so we did this and then we have the weak object over here in the same file which we implemented
the actual thin and demain dot see.
Right.
Okay, so it's looking good so far.
Let's click over here to download, uh, to build first.
So it's building while it's building over here to really capture the essence of what's going on.
We need a different serial program.
Terror term does not give us this are x, t, x functionality in a proper way.
So we're going to, uh, download another one known as real time.
You can go to Google and search download real term.
And at this first link would open once it opens, you just you just follow the, um, the procedure
to to download it.
And then, um, what you do is you click download and once you click download it would open a page,
you will start download enough.
Download this before.
So um.
Yeah.
So it was start downloading shortly.
Right.
You just follow the steps to store.
So to install, you just simply click next.
Keep keep everything the same.
Keep clicking next and then you click to install off, install it before.
So I wouldn't go ahead with this, so I'll cancel this.
OK.
This has finished building.
Oh.
Click debug to get onto the board.
So it's work working from here, you can see getting onto the board.
Right.
Okay.
So we are in debug mode.
I'm going to exit because I just need this to be on the board.
I don't know.
I don't need to debug it.
Okay.
So now I'm going to open the, um, the real term we downloaded and installed.
Oh, open it.
It's called real time.
OK.
Over here.
So this is real time.
So when we start, we have this quote display because I want to show the echo.
I'm going to enable half duplex over here on the do display or enable this import.
Oh, come here.
This dropdown.
What device?
My device is not shown here.
I'll reset my board.
You see, okay, this is my device click connect to window windows, and I have to reset this for it
to show.
So I'm going to open this again.
I'm going to open Real Real-Time again.
Open.
This is real time.
Okay.
I said I'm going to set half duplex.
And on the porch, I'll drop down over here.
USP device.
I know it's put 16.
And I verified that using terror 10.
You can also verify that in your device manager or click 16 over here and under send.
Come over here.
Then I'm going to take.
See our life so that we get a new life.
And what we want to send.
I'm going to send.
This is it.
How about that?
Or hello from Cuba.
Like we did earlier.
So then I click send us and we are sending.
But when I receive it, I see why that is.
Okay.
Simply by pressing the reset button.
I think we are looking good.
No, I just reset my boat.
Nothing has changed.
So Sandusky well is in the yellow is what we receive.
Does the echo.
Right.
If we turn off half duplex here, we really see where we type, so.
Oh, turn this off.
Half duplex and I'll go back to send.
And we seen just one part of the message we're not seeing.
TXI.
We're just seeing Dietrich's OK, so half duplex would give us all of it, put T X and what is brought
back.
Right.
And you can see the LCD is on as well as Sandusky.
And I can see.
OK.
So this is T X outbreaks and you can see the stats showing up when we send we receive us work where
you see the light indicate the activity.
So when I click this, I transmit and receive hands.
We get two sentences.
What is transmitted and what is received.
OK.
So there's a if you have any questions, just live in the questions and answers area.
Oh, see you later.
Have a nice day.